Masshiro na keshiki ni ima sasowarete
Boku wa yuku yo mada minu sekai e
Maigo no mama tabi shiteita
nezumiiro no sora no shita
Higawari no chizu
ikutsumo no yume ga nijinde ita
Itsuka wa sa chippoke na
boku no kono hohaba demo
Ano kumo no mukou made yukeru kana
Tsuyogatte kizutsuita kokoro sukashita you ni
Furidashita amatsubutachi ga
ranhansha kurikaesu
Massugu na hikari ga kousa shite
Yukusaki mo tsugenu mama
dokomademo tsukinukeru
Awai zanzou ryoume ni yakistukete
Kono sora no shita donna toko ni ite mo
Todoku hazu nanda mada minu sekai e
Scar had once again
made an appearance in Central.
Ed and Al worked with Ling to
draw the murderous Ishvalan's attention,
In an effort to lure out the Homunculi.
Their strategy paid off.
Before long, the Homunculi
Wrath and Gluttony appeared.
However...
[SCREAMS]
No! Lan Fan!
Clever.
You took a swipe at me with your kunai.
Can I eat her now?
Just make it quick.
Lan Fan, please stay with me!
If you thought you could
escape from me that easily,
I'm afraid you'll find
you're surely mistaken!
I see you're no stranger to combat.
Ugh!
All this jumping around,
he's trying to stay in my blind spot.
Gluttony!
Excellent.
We should have some privacy in here.
If you don't mind,
I have some questions.
First, I'd like to know who you people are,
and how you found out
what's inside Gluttony.
You're looking for an escape? Even now?
You don't give up, do you?
You might stand a fair chance of getting
away if you'd only abandon the injured girl
because she's just excess
baggage at this point.
Excess baggage?
I can see all those stars on your uniform.
You're the ruler here.
Führer King Bradley, unless I'm mistaken.
A ruler's duty is to his people.
Without them, he is no king at all!
King Bradley, you're no true king.
Not now or ever!
Naive boy.
Don't you understand that there
are no true kings in this world?
[EXPLOSION]
[BRADLEY GROANS]
That oughtta hold him.
Judging by the draft, there's the exit.
Nice try.
But your flash bomb didn't
succeed in blinding this eye.
[GASPS]
Winry.
We won't be away too long.
You be a good little girl, okay?
Take care of things while we're gone.
Winry?
Huh?
Here we are.
Watching Mr. Hughes leave that day
was like the last time I saw Mom and Dad.
Just their backs as they walked away.
You'll come and visit
once in a while, won't you?
After all, we wouldn't want
him to get lonesome here.
Yes, of course I will.
I hear the Elrics are wreaking havoc.
What? Again?
The MPs have been
running around like crazy.
They're in another fight?
Good grief.
It seems they're after that guy
who's been killing off state alchemists.
Seriously? They haven't caught him yet?
What is the military waiting for?
No. Not again, please!
Ah!
It's a dead end!
Damn! What now?!
Nice one, brother!
Appreciate it!
We need to get out of here now!
Permission to fire?
Not yet.
Why the hell not?
Ling hasn't fired the signal flare yet.
And brother's getting tired.
I have to buy us some time.
Scar!
You say you believe that
alchemists have defied God.
Isn't that hypocritical?
You use alchemy just like we do.
I explained it when we met in East City.
It's balance.
Where there are creators,
there must be a destroyer.
That's a lie!
You're using the name of
your god to justify murder!
Revenge is all you care about.
When you killed Shou Tucker and Nina...
I suppose you believe you
were doing God's work then, too!
Interesting.
You two saw that abomination
as well, did you?
Alchemy created that tragic creature.
So that's the science you
would spend your lives following?
Look at your brother!
He's the result of messing
around with somebody's life!
That chimera was made
because a man thought he could
create when creation is
the province of God alone.
[GASP]
Maybe you're right.
But why did you have to kill her?
You stole what little life she had left!
Foolish as you are, you must
still have known that chimera...
could never have returned
to her human state.
[GASPS]
It would have lived out its
life as a laboratory specimen.
Treated as a test subject,
but never again as a human being.
He's right.
Even then, we knew that Nina
would be sent off to live in a laboratory.
We knew full well what would happen to her.
We didn't wanna think about it.
We knew there was no hope.
So we did nothing.
Nothing.
[FOOTSTEPS]
It's true. State Alchemists have
made some serious mistakes
But despite what you think,
that doesn't make
what you're doing right.
And we can't let you continue!
You're so self-righteous.
But do you remember two
Amestrian doctors named Rockbell?
The order came down
to end the uprising and
exterminate Ishval,
but that didn't stop them.
They kept right on helping your people!
Wait, brother!
Don't you remember them?
Those doctors saved your
life, and you killed them!
Brother!
What are you talking about, Ed?
Winry, I...
You mean he's the man...
who killed them?
My parents?
He killed them?
What's worse...
They helped save you...
And you killed them.
Why did you?
They were my mom and dad.
What did they ever do to you?
They were doctors.
They helped people.
They didn't deserve to die!
[SOBS]
Give them back!
Give me back my mom and dad, you monster!
[SOBBING]
Winry, hold on...
You can't.
Don't do this.
Winry!
Don't do it!
I know the animosity you feel,
but your vengeance will only
sow the seeds of further violence.
What you're doing is senseless revenge, and
it's feeding a fruitless cycle of death.
You must end this cycle once and for all.
Fullmetal Alchemist.
This girl is the doctors' daughter.?
You have the right.
Shooting me would be justified.
Brother!
Listen.
The armed forces have almost arrived.
This is no time to be
looking at your notes.
Just a minute more. I'm almost there.
What are those tattoos for?
Oh, these things?
The basis of alchemy is understanding
deconstruction, and reconstruction.
My right arm deconstructs.
My left arm reconstructs.
I studied the alkahestry they use in the
East and then added my own touches.
I discovered something else in my research.
The alchemy of this land is quite unusual.
None of that stuff matters anymore,
didn't you hear me?
The army is here!
Stop.
Why are you interfering?
We have to get away from here now!
Please, calm down and listen.
Your brother's alchemy might be
the only way we have of saving Ishval.
What?
You must have heard.
The enemy has State Alchemists.
They're weapons.
Using their dirty magic to cut a path
of destruction through the country.
Even though we're
Amestrian citizens just like them.
I've heard all about the military dogs.
But what do they have to do
with my brother's research?
Your brother is the only one who
can stand against the State Alchemists.
If he can match their power with his,
he could find a way to annihilate the military.
The threat to us would be ended!
Kill them before they can kill us.
Take them down.
With alchemy, we'll beat
them at their own game.
Pay them back in blood.
Do you see this, brother?
This is the science that you
would spend your life following.
You may think it's for the greater good,
that it could help our people.
You don't even see
the evil you're creating!
Run!
[SCREAMS AND MARCHING]
So this is your alchemy, brother?
[LAUGHING]
This is the great power?
This is going to save our people?
This science causes nothing
but destruction and slaughter.
It can't save us.
Oh, no!
Father! Mother!
Are you all right?
Yes, we're both okay.
Luckily, we were already prepared to flee
from here in case we needed to.
Sorry I'm late.
There were some important
notes I needed to compile.
What do you mean?
Here. I want you to hold on to this.
Why? What is it?
These are my research notes.
This is all that I was able to bring.
Take them and get away now.
Hold on a minute—
If anything happens to me, I don't want
my research to have been for nothing.
Why don't you just take
it and run away yourself?
Because you're a warrior
of the Ishvalan people.
You've been well trained.
Let's be honest here,
You're a lot more likely
to survive this than I am.
Just look.
My legs won't stop shaking.
Some big brother.
You will survive.
Is that a soldier?
Look at his hands!
He's a State Alchemist!
Get back!
Ahh!
Stay with me.
Don't you die.
Damn.
I can't stop the bleeding.
His arm...
Where's my brother's arm?
Where is it?
Father...
Mother...
Someone?
Anyone?!
Don't die.
I won't let you.
I have to keep fighting.
Let me go back out there.
No. You're staying right where you are.
That's right.
We didn't treat you just to let you die.
Doctor, you and your
wife should get out of here.
Young man, we're not going anywhere.
Brother...
Get back!
What happened?
Why did you protect me?
Brother?
Anyone who can move on their own, go now.
He's awake!
Don't move or you'll open up your wounds.
Come here.
Dear, come here.
You aren't well enough to
move around on your own yet.
Somebody, get a cart.
Take this man with you.
He needs help.
Brother's tattoos...
You're alive.
Brother, you've made it.
[GASP]
What is going on here?!
Sedatives!
There aren't any more.
We used them all up!
State Alchemist.
Amestrians.
You will pay.
[CRASH]
All of you.
- All of you will pay...
- Doctor Rockbell!
[SCREAMS]
Go on, shoot.
Don't do it, Winry.
Put down the gun.
You know you don't wanna do this.
Winry!
Shoot, girl.
But know, the moment
you pull the trigger,
There's no going back,
you will be my enemy.
Scar!
If you think I'll let you hurt
one hair on her head—
Will you kill me?
That'd be fine with me.
Until one of us dies, boy,
this chain of hatred will continue.
But don't ever forget!
Don't ever forget it was the Amestrians
who first pulled the
trigger during the Civil War.
It was your people!
Winry, don't shoot.
Just put the gun down and get out of here.
Winry!
If you can't shoot, then
do as the boy told you.
You're in my way.
Don't shoot!
Get back!
My brother...
Ed, you idiot, what are you doing?
Both of you will get killed!
Hurry and get Winry somewhere safe.
Winry, let go of the gun.
I couldn't shoot.
I know you couldn't.
And it's okay.
But that man...
You said he's the one
who killed my mom and dad.
He tried to kill you and Al too, Ed.
But I couldn't.
Why not?
Remember in Rush Valley,
you delivered that baby?
You saved two lives.
And you gave me an arm and a leg,
to replace the ones I've lost.
It's your hands.
They weren't meant to kill.
They're meant to give life.
That's why.
[SOBBING]
Let it all out, let it all out
Tsuyogaranakute ii n da ne
Dareka ga kaite'tta
Kabe no rakugaki no hana ga yureru
Jibunrashisa nante, dare mo wakaranai yo
Nagai nagai michi no tochuu
de nakushitari, hirottari,
Kyuu ni samishiku natte,
naichau hi mo aru kedo
Namida mo itami mo, hoshi ni kaeyou
Ashita wo terasu akari wo tomosou
Chiisana te kazashite
futari de tsukurou hoshikuzu wo
Tsuyoku hikaru ein wo
Sayonara itsuka wa kuru ka mo shirenu
Kisetsu wa sore demo meguri megutte'ku
Chiisaku mayotte mo aruite'ku
Kimi to aruite'ku
Sore daku wa kawaranaide iyou ne
What happens when someone must
give something up, in order to protect it?
Will his resolve falter?
Will he crumble beneath
the weight of sacrifice?
Or will his heart remain strong,
ready to do whatever is necessary?
Next time on Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood
Episode 23: Girl on the Battlefield
You must not show any tears of sorrow.
That is part of the promise.